{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Yeast Replicating plasmids (YRp) carry", "opta": "centromere", "optb": "telomere", "optc": "autonomously replicating sequence", "optd": "both (a) and (c)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following viruses are used as vectors for transferring genes to animal cells?", "opta": "SV 40 virus", "optb": "Bovine papilloma virus (BVP)", "optc": "Retroviruses", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Recombinant adeno virus can be created by deleting E1A/E 1B genes that are", "opta": "transcriptional regulators and are essential for viral replication", "optb": "not necessary for viral replication", "optc": "coding for virus coat protein", "optd": "important for packaging of viral DNA into viral head", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Retroviruses have advantage for being used as vector for animal cells because", "opta": "they cover a wide host range", "optb": "infection does not lead to cell death, infected cells produce virus over an indefinite period", "optc": "viral gene expression is driven by strong promoters", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Using bovine papilloma virus (BPV) derived vectors, permanent cell lines can be obtained carrying a recombinant DNA", "opta": "episomally only", "optb": "integrated only", "optc": "either episomally or integrated at high copy number", "optd": "either episomally or integrated at low copy number", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following histone is not present in SV40 virus?", "opta": "H1", "optb": "H2A", "optc": "H3", "optd": "H4", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Autonomously replicating sequence is not present in", "opta": "YIp", "optb": "YRp", "optc": "YCp", "optd": "YAC", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In case of Baculoviruses, the foreign gene", "opta": "is inserted downstream of polyhedrin promoter", "optb": "is inserted downstream of viral origin of replication", "optc": "is inserted between the polyhedrin promoter and downstream sequences", "optd": "is inserted randomly in viral genome", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "\u03b1-aminoadipate inhibits the growth if one of the following marker is present in the yeast. That is", "opta": "His 3", "optb": "Lys 2", "optc": "Ura 3", "optd": "Trp 1", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Yeast episomal plasmids (YEp) were constructed using", "opta": "2\u03bcm yeast plasmid, fragments of yeast nuclear DNA and E coli vector pMB 9", "optb": "2\u03bcm yeast plasmid, fragments of yeast nuclear DNA and E coli vector pBR 322", "optc": "12\u03bcm yeast plasmid and E coli vector pMB 9", "optd": "12\u03bcm yeast plasmid and E coli vector pBR 322", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is/are commonly used promoter of S. cerevisiae?", "opta": "Galactokinase (GAL 1)", "optb": "Alcohol dehydrogenase II (ADH 2)", "optc": "Phosphoglycerate kinase (PGK)", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Maximum amount of foreign DNA introduced into SV 40 viruses is", "opta": "10 kb", "optb": "5 kb", "optc": "2.5 kb", "optd": "1 kb", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Recombinant SV40 viruses introduce the foreign DNA into cells", "opta": "with the DNA mediated transfection", "optb": "without the DNA mediated transfection", "optc": "with the RNA mediated transfection", "optd": "without the RNA mediated transfection", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following is the most stable vector?", "opta": "YEp", "optb": "YRp", "optc": "YAC", "optd": "YIp", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "SV 40 vectors, in which early region replacements are carried out, require", "opta": "COS cell line", "optb": "SV 40 helper virus", "optc": "pBR 322 vector", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cloning genes in the yeast offer which of following advantage(s)?", "opta": "Over production of proteins of commercial value", "optb": "Ability to glycosylate proteins during secretion", "optc": "Ability to clone large piece of DNA", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following is true about Yeast Episomal plasmids (YEp) vectors?", "opta": "Allows transformation by using crossing over", "optb": "Has a origin of replication and rep genes", "optc": "Carries autonomously replicating sequence", "optd": "Carries centromere and telomere sequences", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following is true about Yeast Centromeric plasmids (YCp) vectors?", "opta": "Contains centromeric sequences", "optb": "Segregates during meiosis and mitosis", "optc": "Functions as true chromosome", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Autographa California nuclear polyhedrosis virus that is used as a vector for animal cells is an example of", "opta": "Vaccinia virus", "optb": "Baculo virus", "optc": "Papilloma virus", "optd": "Retrovirus", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Polyhedrin protein is", "opta": "non essential for baculo virus replication", "optb": "major component of protein matrix in which viruses are embedded", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "essential for baculo virus replication", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cos cell line is", "opta": "cohesive end site of phage \u03bb", "optb": "derivative of permissive CV-1 monkey cell line", "optc": "cohesive initial site of phage \u03bb", "optd": "derivative of non-permissive CV-1 monkey cell line", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lytic infection of SV 40 does not occur in", "opta": "permissive cells", "optb": "non permissive cells", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Moloney-Mu-leukemia virus is an example of", "opta": "Vaccinia virus", "optb": "Baculo virus", "optc": "Retro virus", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following is true about Yeast Integrative plasmids (YIp) vectors?", "opta": "Allows transformation by using crossing over", "optb": "Has a origin of replication and rep genes", "optc": "Carries autonomously replicating sequence", "optd": "Carries centromere and telomere sequences", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The size of the genome of SV 40 is", "opta": "7.2 kb", "optb": "69 kb", "optc": "5.2 kb", "optd": "110 kb", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "YAC vectors can be used to obtain artificial chromosomes because it carries", "opta": "centromere", "optb": "telomere", "optc": "autonomously replicating sequence", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Maximum insert size in case of adenovirus vectors is", "opta": "6-8 kb", "optb": "4-6 kb", "optc": "10-12 kb", "optd": "20 kb", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "SV 40 vectors, in which late region replacements are done, require", "opta": "COS cell line", "optb": "SV 40 helper virus", "optc": "pBR 322 vector", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following(s) is/are the most commonly used markers in yeast?", "opta": "His 3", "optb": "Ura 3", "optc": "Trp 1", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following are produced in high copy number?", "opta": "YEp", "optb": "YRp", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "YCp", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "5-fluoro orotic acid inhibits the growth if one of the following marker is present in the yeast. That is", "opta": "His 3", "optb": "Lys 2", "optc": "Ura 3", "optd": "Trp 1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following promoters is repressed in presence of glucose?", "opta": "Galactokinase (GAL 1)", "optb": "Acid phosphatase (PHOS)", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Phosphoglycerate kinase (PGK)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following can be used for reducing the size of gene inserts containing introns?", "opta": "Vaccinia virus", "optb": "Baculo virus", "optc": "Retro virus", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bovine papilloma virus has a circular double stranded DNA genome of about", "opta": "2.5 kb", "optb": "5.2 kb", "optc": "7.9 kb", "optd": "9.5 kb", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Retroviruses consist of", "opta": "Ds DNA genome", "optb": "Ss DNA genome", "optc": "RNA genome", "optd": "cDNA genome", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}